And that's breakpoint for Sarukawa.
It's the middle of the second set.
They've taken the lead for the first time today, Joe.
Well, they just keep hitting it back, don't they?
To the worst of all possible spots every time.
Even when they do all of the right things
and can score a point, they deliberately don't do it.
It's a strategy they've been cleverly incorporating
into all of their plays.
When you're actually standing on the court
and coming face-to-face with the other team's attacks,
things don't always go the way you planned on the whiteboard.
But they have the self-control to pull it off.
As well as the intelligence and composure
to look at the game as a whole.
You've got a bunch of great players over there.
Aritaka.
Crush him.
That setter's been coddled by those A-Passes
who passes for too long.
Crush him.
since internet.
Fire him.
JCimi Messi
Noah Goku
never Ram
N
Bye for now.
Bye.
Nice receive!
Come on guys, it wasn't actually that nice.
Nice kill!
Bit higher next time.
Sorry.
With number 4 Yamamoto lined up next to them,
number 1 Kuro and number 11 Haiba
form a very powerful center zone combination for Nekomada.
I'm sure Sarakawa knew going in
that they'd have to watch out when those three were together.
Indeed, it would seem Sarakawa's blockers
must have had all their attention on Lev Haiba during that play.
Well, Kenma, you look really tired right now.
Please shut up.
So the setter, he seems pretty weak from what I can tell.
If you'd known that, couldn't you guys have gone after him too?
Well, that's actually a tricky thing.
As a general rule, the setter's usually the second player to hit the ball, not the first.
And going after somebody with a serve or something is a pretty standard strategy.
But to keep putting indirect pressure on someone little by little like that,
that takes a lot of patience and a lot of courage.
he is bodyISAHBA's blockers
קי
Jetzt
Argh!
Nu
he
Đ
Uh-oh! It looks like the young star has tripped over his own feet!
Lucky Lucky Sarikawa! Lucky Lucky Sarikawa!
Being a setter does require moving around quite a lot.
The position is much harder than most people realize.
It may seem like a monotonous repetition of one point at a time,
but the pressure will add up slowly but surely.
A single kill block isn't as effective as a one-touch five times,
or pressuring the other team ten times.
One perfect A pass isn't any better than five B passes or ten C passes
as long as the ball gets in the air.
And remember, the stronger our opponent,
the more important it will be for us to consider the flow of the entire game.
Instead of going for the one perfect point,
work on accumulating those 100 boring points that will win you the game.
Sir!
You okay?
I look pathetic.
And we haven't even played two full sets yet.
Man, my hands are all numb.
Everybody looks pathetic when they're trying that hard.
I guess, but could you try not to sound so happy about it?
Sarukawa has the upper hand in this set for sure,
so it wouldn't be a bad idea to focus on the final set
and let Kenma sit out and rest.
Oh, look.
Great minds think alike.
All right, guys. Just one more push.
It's all good. Let's keep attacking.
Oh, so close.
He aimed for the perfect spot, but just barely missed it, Joe.
You're still winning this set.
Now's the time to keep pushing through.
Don't panic, boys.
One touch!
Follow through! Follow through!
Zowa!
Oh, that was a nice one!
It's short.
Sarukawa Tech keeps hitting Nekama's weak spots.
It really seems to be messing with their heads.
As we near the end of the set, Nekama's made a push,
and now we are all tied up!
It was a bit of a scramble, but they got the ball to the right side
where the defense was lightest.
Okay, they're warming up to some of our plays now,
but they are not there yet.
Don't start rushing.
Yes, sir!
Sorry!
No worries.
Serve it up, Korra!
A nice, slow serve to the front,
but did Nekama's receive go too far to the side, Joe?
No!
Come on now, you're better than that.
This is when you really need to get the ball up there.
Over here.
Wait.
Did they do that on purpose?
To lure our blockers away from the left side?
Stay there!
They figured it out.
Okay.
We'll go to the right there.
Yeah!
And Nobuyuki Kai makes it count!
This time they chose the right side despite the narrow opening.
Sarikawa's blockers may be a little shell-shocked.
At a glance, the young setter is very unassuming,
but he may be the sneakiest little rascal in this championship.
Sorry, that one wound up being a bit short.
It's all good.
Okay, listen up.
They might have changed direction on that receive on purpose.
Do you think they're trying to fake out our blockers?
What?
To fake?
But that would mean they...
Wait.
Not when did this start?
I guess their strategy is to get Kenma to run around.
Looks like it.
Huh?
What?
Why would they do that?
Inuoka?
Right.
Well, it's pretty simple.
You know what it ain't passes, right?
Yeah.
I don't suppose any of you have some great strategy,
where we beat these guys without me running all over the place?
Yeah, Tremont.
Never expected to hear Kenma say something so stupid.
If you're going to defeat the patient persevering strategy they're using,
then I'd say you're going to need some patient perseverance of your own.
Hmm.
Then it's time for us to adapt.
Huh?
I don't suppose any of you have some great strategy,
where we beat these guys without me running all over the place?
Yeah, Tremont.
Never expected to hear Kenma say something so stupid.
If you're going to defeat the patient persevering strategy they're using,
then I'd say you're going to need some patient perseverance of your own.
Hmm.
Then it's time for us to adapt.
Time for us receivers, that is.
Gee, thanks.
Yeah, maybe it's overprotective,
but making sure our setter stays put is the neck of my way.
Hmm.
But...
Hmm?
An ordinary battle of wills is never any fun.
What?
You're telling us to do sloppy receives on purpose?
Yeah, it's not like it's never been done before, but...
I don't mean on every receipt,
just on particular ones when the timing is right.
I mean, we can get the ball up whenever you need it,
but you're pretty wiped out already.
Are you going to be okay out there?
I'm capable of moving around, you know, just not much.
I mean, obviously I wouldn't want to have to run all the way to the end line
and back every time,
but these tactics will be harder on you guys anyway.
You already have to get used to Sarukawa's attacks.
On top of that, you still got to get the ball where I need it on every play.
But...
You can do it.
Because you guys can all use guts.
What else do you need from us, Kenma?
One more thing.
Could you get the ball up high?
You got it, my man!
It's mine!
They're probably watching out for Kuro and Lev, for our attacks to come in the center zone.
That basically means any ball they block will end up going towards our middle.
And their whole plan revolves around trying to crush me specifically.
That's why they're going to fall for this.
They'll believe that these are just sloppy passes.
We'll use the ball and our middle blockers to get their blockers' attention.
While I set the ball far, far away.
And then...
Stay there!
We'll realize what's going on.
That's when we aim for the other side.
Nobuyuki Kai scores again from the right side!
That's when Kai pushing Kai one more time!
Wait...
Now when did this start?
Just a coincidence.
It's just one point.
Don't freak out!
Let's all just stay focused on closing out this set.
Got it!
No way!
Was this planned from the start?
We tried manipulating them, but they were doing it to us!
They brought out the backup setter, but there's no sign of them swapping him in.
Was it just to get our guard down?
Maybe Nekoma Setter isn't really as tired as we think he is.
You've certainly got some great players over there, Aritaka.
But as usual, things don't always go the way you planned them in the locker room.
Doubt leads to paranoia.
Huh?
Absolutely perfect timing!
You didn't make any mistakes.
The pressure you've been putting on them is working.
Nekoma Setter is definitely wearing down.
They're a powerhouse, no plan's gonna be perfect.
But we're hanging in there just fine.
Let's give them another big push!
Right!
If Nekoma has been making those sloppy passes on purpose,
it means they knew Sarukawa was trying to wear Kenma down,
and then adopted a strategy that would make it even worse for them.
Are they friggin' crazy?
There's no easy victory here.
I know what this is!
It's a deuce, right?
Oh, that's right.
The longer it goes, the more exhausted everyone gets.
Big time.
Nice receive!
If this game goes long, you're the ones who will suffer, not us.
Their plan was to crush Kenma over time.
But they forgot we're Nekoma.
We'll just make the proper adjustments.
Nice receive!
We settle it at the end of the second set.
Everyone will have adapted to the other team.
Patience, don't rush it!
And then, the moment Sarukawa closes in for the set,
we get our breakpoint and take the whole game.
Well, that was the plan anyway.
Everything was going so well, too.
But they're so damn stubborn!
Hmm?
Would you just...
Let it hit the ground already?
Lucky, lucky, lucky, lucky!
We won't let you win!
This battle of wills!
Go, go, go, go!
Both teams are masters of defense and unwilling to back down.
You can feel the tension from the court all over the arena, Chip!
I should've just told them I'd work extra hard the third set
and ask to sit out for the second.
Why does gravity have to be a thing?
Gravity, you're pissing me off!
If it weren't for gravity, the ball wouldn't fall into our court!
The ball only falls because of stupid gravity!
If we run the moon...
Kenma, focus!
Concentration is the one thing Kenma has in spades,
and even he's starting to lose it.
He won't last much longer.
Well, it looks like you better get warmed up again.
Yes, sir.
Okay, well what about you?
Don't try to talk to me about guts when you don't even have any!
Ever since Taurus said that to me, I've been asking myself what that word really means.
Guts.
I've always kind of hated that word.
These days I'm pretty sure society's not too fond of it either.
When people say it, it's like they think it's something you can just turn on whenever you feel like it.
But lately, I've been thinking.
Whether you're one of those who loves the word, or one of those who hates it,
the difficulty level involved in turning it on when you need it is much higher than anyone on either side thinks.
I think guts is an ultimate secret move.
It can only be activated at just the right moment by those who have trained up their bodies and souls.
But it's a special move that I can't use.
All of these rallies have been super long.
Front!
One touch!
Get to the ball.
A half step quicker.
That half step will give you what you need to control the ball.
The fatigue has got to be getting to them by now.
They can't last forever.
But their plays are still so measured and deliberate.
They know we're baiting them.
They know we can attack from either side.
They're watching for every possibility.
When that happens, you keep it simple.
And go straight to the middle.
And there's break points!
Nekama is finally able to sit the scales!
Way to go, Kuro!
Because you guys can all use guts.
I bet you're over there thinking you can't do this.
It's true.
You never try and stand your ground.
And you're always looking for ways to get out of stuff.
But even if you were last, or if you were whining the whole time,
whether our coaches and upperclassmen were watching or not,
you always see things through until the end!
Zari!
Cover!
Now, Fukunaga's on the left.
He's good, so he'll still be able to make that point, even if there are blockers.
Zori! Cover!
Right now, Fukunaga's on the left.
He's good, so he'll still be able to make that point, even if there are blockers.
So does your school have a good volleyball team, or what?
But I'm not good.
We are together.
I've only ever seen him do that after an A-Pass.
With minimal movement, he performs a perfect set.
And there it is, Joe, after the seemingly endless deuce victory is finally found by Nekamaha.
That was well played by Kozume.
Not once did he ever give the blockers a chance to read him for a second during that entire game.
He truly gave everything he had out there.
Not bad, stolen bread.
Thank you very much for coming!
Thank you for coming!
We'll have to try harder next time.
Your boys really hung tough.
Defense Master Nekamaha.
I thought by this point, you'd be a lot less warlike.
Well, to be perfectly honest, sometimes the boys themselves are more warlike than I am.
That said, I want you to know you're worthy opponents.
Very well played.
Thank you, sir.
You really stood firm today, Kenma.
I barely believe it.
Who would have thought you would suggest a plan that would basically make you pass out if it worked?
I just pushed myself during the second set so we wouldn't have to play a third one.
There's no way I could do three sets of that.
Sarakawa would have crushed me into dust.
So, hey, Kenma.
When you fell earlier, was that all a part of the act, too?
I'm not really a good enough actor to fake that.
Oh, sure.
That makes sense.
You finally showed some guts, Kenma.
I really didn't.
I'm not a high enough level to use guts.
What?
I guess it was just that, oh, I don't know.
I felt like I owed you guys.
You were all working so hard to get the ball up for me that I felt I had to do my part, too.
I guess.
That's what I'm saying.
That was guts.
Look, I just did what I could, okay?
Do you really have to put a label on everything?
Is it that weird for me to work for something?
What are you so mad about?
Speaking of, I think I heard you getting mad at gravity during that set.
Okay, man.
Your personality changes way too much when you're tired.
You must be low on carbohydrates.
You should probably have a banana.
Is it so weird for someone to put in some effort for their team?
Huh?
Or is it just weird when I do it?
That it?
Oh, man.
You, you try!
Oh, God!
You stay away!
Yamamoto's overreacting again.
Not this time.
You finally showed us your guts!
It's pretty rare for Kenma to admit he's part of a group, so I'd say that reaction is fair.
Give me a hug!
Back, animals!
Fukunaga, please don't encourage him!
No, man, you do!
Now, if only Kenma could be half as aggressive whenever he's playing volleyball, as he gets
when he's in his own world playing his stupid video games...
Don't narrate your own version of my thoughts.
On second thought, I still hate guts.
The difficulty level is just too high.
But, I definitely leveled up.
And if we're gonna play, I wanna fight the strongest bosses.
I guess there's one guy that gets Kenma to start acting aggressive, so that's good.
Heck yeah!
So, Karasuno's up against the Mia twins.
Whoa, it looks like they already took the first set off those guys.
Hmm.
Guess what, Karasuno?
We're here.
And now, we're coming for you.
確かなことはいつか
わかるときが来るから
街が立っていさ
今、思いを止めないで
現実が飛んじゃうような
夢が欲しかったのに
辻褄を合わすだけの日々は
味気ない
何にも怖くなんて泣いて
強がって馬鹿の少年が
今もまだ汗ばむ背中を
見つめてるから
奇跡はもういらない
どこまでだって
いける僕らは
ファンデ
夢も叶うさ
ここまでやってきたのは
偶然なんかじゃなくて
去ってしまう舞台に
だって
痛いと
いつでも
強く願い続けた
君が
そこにいたから
次回は
The Ultimate Challengers
ファンデ